Getting a good grade from a subject,
在一個學科取得優等成績，
is seen by most students and parents as the most easy
會被大多數學生和家長視為最簡單明瞭的辦法，
and simple measure of results in school.
去衡量上學的成就。
Now, how are classes graded at Bodwell?
現在,博域中學是怎樣評定各班成績的呢?
Grades are in the form of an average percentage
成績等級的形式可以是一個平均百份比，
ora letter grade.
或是一個英文字母。
For example, a student getting 95 in Physics 11 is an A
例如: 一名學生在第11年級物理科拿到95分,他就是個A等生。
That shows a very high overall achievement by the student in Physics 11.
那表示該名第11年級物理科同學的整體成績非常高。
Then there are B, C, and Fail.
其他等級還有：Ｂ等，Ｃ等，及不合格。
What is the fuller meaning involved in the grade?
成績等級還有什麼更多的意思嗎？
In fact, how much a student understands, thinks, and uses knowledge in any subject
實際上，學生對某個科目有多少認識、思考、知識運用，
is not told by just one letter grade of A or B or C.
都不能僅僅以字母Ａ、Ｂ或Ｃ來說明。
A master teacher uses many ways
科目老師用許多方法
to observe, measure, and provide feedback
來觀察和衡量學生的學習、思考、
on a student's learning, thinking, and understanding.
及理解能力，並給予反饋。
Mostly, a student learns and presents his learning by answering questions,
在多數情況下，學生是透過回答口頭或書面問題，
oral or written,
例如問答、測驗和考試等形式來學習，
in the form of quizzes, tests, and exams.
及呈現其學習成果。
When these are the same across classes or schools.
當統一用於同級各班組或各學校時，
We use the term "Standardized Assessment".
我們會用上＂標準化評核＂這個詞。
A student also learns by discussing, arguing,
其他學習方法還有:討論、辨論、
solving problems, designing and completing a project,
解決問題、設計並完成作業項目、
and working with other students.
以及跟其他同學的合作。
Good teachers observe all these actions
優秀的老師會觀察同學們所有那些作為，
and give students feedback to provoke further thinking and questioning.
並給予反饋，以引起進一步的思考和發問。
The teacher is measuring the student's learning
老師量度學生的學習進度，
Through a "Formative Process".
是通過一種”形成性過程”來做的。
All performances combined into one, final grade.
所有課業成績合計，可得出一個最終的等級。
A final grade for a subject will mean
一個科目的最終成績等級，
combining all that a students learns from
綜合了一個學生的全部所學,包括:
quizzes, tests, and exams
問答、測驗、考試、
discussions, homework, group projects, and presentations.
討論、家課、集體作業、作業匯報等。
What is a G.P.A.? - Grade Point Average
什麼是G.P.A.呢? (“成績等級平均分”的英文縮寫)
Transcripts give a G.P.A.
成績表上打出的G.P.A.分數，
meaning that the letter grades are changed into points.
是由字母等級轉換而來。
A is 4, B-3, C-2. D or "PASS" - 1, Fail is a 0.
A是4分, B 3分, C 2分, D或 “PASS”(合格)是1分, Fail(不合格)是0分。
The in-betweens of A and B and C and D are a half point.
介乎A與B與C與D之間的是半分。
All points of various subjects are added
然後,把各個科目的所有分數相加，
then divided by the number of subjects.
再除以科目的數目。
If you still have questions about grades and G.P.A.,
如果你對成績等級和G.P.A.仍然有問題，
Please speak to any teacher or counsellor.
請與任何一位老師或輔導老師洽商。